Guide to the Anderson family Papers, 1848-1963
Department of Special Collections
- THE DIAL Correspondence, 1890 - 1891 (Box 11, Folder 62)
- THE DIAL Correspondence, 1892 - 1898 (Box 11, Folder 63)
- THE DIAL Correspondence, 1899 - 1901 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  The Dial Correspondence is a collection of letters from Francis Fisher Browne, editor of THE DIAL. These letters are essentially personal, but they contain many comments on the affairs of the times. Browne lived in Chicago, had been a soldier in the Union Army, had a large family, and was greatly concerned with the literary, political, and social affairs of his era. He and Melville Best Anderson were close friends and Browne published many of Anderson's reviews, essays and comments on literary subjects.
- THE DIAL Correspondence, 1903 - 1906 (Box 12, Folder 65)
- THE DIAL Correspondence, 1907 - 1913 (Box 12, Folder 66)
- THE DIAL Correspondence, 1913 - 1920 (Box 12, Folder 67)
- Letters from readers of THE DIAL, mostly concerning articles by Anderson on Matthew Arnold in 1888 (Box 12, Folder 68)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson, General Correspondence, C - Cleland (Box 12, Folder 69)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson, General Correspondence, Coe - Cox (Box 12, Folder 70)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson, General Correspondence, Cracroft - Cycling club. (Box 12, Folder 71)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson Edward Gordon Craig, (Special Folder) (Box 12, Folder 72)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson Albert S. Cook, (Special Folder) (Box 13, Folder 73)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson Agnes Smith Mannucci-Capponi Special copy of The Great Refusal Special Folder (Box 13, Folder 74)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, D - Dunning (Box 13, Folder 75)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson Emma Frances Dawson, (Special Folder) (Box 13, Folder 76)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence E - Swing (Box 13, Folder 77)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, F - Fukukita (Box 13, Folder 78)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson Ewald Flügel, (Special Folder) (Box 13, Folder 79)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson French Wounded Emergency Fund., (Special Folder) (Box 14, Folder 80)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, G - Grinnell (Box 14, Folder 81)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson Edward Howard Griggs, (Special Folder) (Box 14, Folder 82)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson, Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Louisa van Vleck and Balfour Anderson from Ellen Graydon, Katherine Graydon, Mary Graydon and Julia Graydon., (Special Folder) (Box 14, Folder 83)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson, Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Malcolm Anderson and Balfour Anderson from Irene Hardy., (Special Folder) (Box 14, Folder 84)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence H - Hayse (Box 14, Folder 85)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Heagle - Hoover 4 letters from Lou Henry Hoover (Box 15, Folder 86)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence Howard - Huxley (Box 15, Folder 87)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence I (Box 15, Folder 88)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General correspondence J - Johnson (Box 15, Folder 89)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence Jones - Jury (Box 15, Folder 90)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence K (Box 15, Folder 91)
- David Starr Jordan. Portrait by Melville Best Anderson and Random Reminiscences of Our Early Acquaintance by Melville Best Anderson (Box 15, Folder 92)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan and Susan B. Jordan to Melville Best Anderson and Charlena van Vleck Anderson 1873 - 1879 (Box 15, Folder 93)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan to Melville Best Anderson 1880 - 1889 (Box 16, Folder 94)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan to Melville Best Anderson 1890 - 1896 (Box 16, Folder 95)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan to Melville Best Anderson 1900 - 1910 (Box 16, Folder 96)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan to Melville Best Anderson 1911 - 1920 (Box 16, Folder 97)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan to Melville Best Anderson 1921 - 1927 (Box 16, Folder 98)
- Letters from David Starr Jordan to M.B. Anderson - 1931 (Box 16, Folder 98.-1)
  David Starr Jordan and Melville Best Anderson were friends for most of their lives. They were at Cornell University at the same time and later taught in the same town. Anderson came to Stanford when Jordan became President.
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence L - Leddy (Box 16, Folder 99)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence Lees - Lyon (Box 17, Folder 100)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson McClure Correspondence S. S. McClure and John Phillips. S. S. McClure was the Editor of MC CLURES MAGAZINE, (Special Folder) (Box 17, Folder 101)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson John Muir (Naturalist), (Special Folder) (Box 17, Folder 102)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, M - Marti (Box 17, Folder 103)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Mason - Mivieri (Box 17, Folder 104)
- Letterst to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Modern Language - Moulton (Box 17, Folder 105)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence N (Box 18, Folder 106)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, O (Box 18, Folder 107)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Palmer - Perkins (Box 18, Folder 108)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, W. R. Perkins - Putnam (Box 18, Folder 109)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Q (Box 19, Folder 110)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, R (Box 19, Folder 111)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, S - Sewell (Box 19, Folder 112)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Shambaugh - S. Smith (Box 19, Folder 113)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Snow - Stillman (Box 19, Folder 114)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Stoddard - Super (Box 19, Folder 115)
- Miscellaneous Material regarding Stanford University. One letter from Mrs. Stanford (Box 19, Folder 116)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, T (Box 20, Folder 117)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, U (Box 20, Folder 118)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, V (Box 20, Folder 119)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, W - White (Box 20, Folder 120)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, Willard - Wylie (Box 20, Folder 121)
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson from Anna Strunsky Walling, (Special Folder) (Box 20, Folder 122)
  Huntington letters from MBA to ANNA STRUNSKY WALLING
- Letters to Melville Best Anderson General Correspondence, X, Y, Z (Box 20, Folder 123)
- Container 21 holds Journals, Account Books, note books and Diaries. All are by Melville Best Anderson. (Box 21)
  - a. Ledger book, accounts, notes 1865 - 1874
  - b. Pocket Diary -- Class book(notes and lists of students, etc.) 1872
  - c. Pocket Diary -- also entries for 1875 and 1876. 1874
  - d. Class notes, European History lectures delivered by Goldin Smith at Cornell University. Also copies of poems by William Rupelt, Dudley, Roswell Leavitt, David Starr Jordan, Melville Best Anderson, George A. Berry, Reynaldos di Nuntalvan and a play in verse, by Melville Best Anderson
  - e. Mental Portraits Also Class Notes, Geology
  - f. Year Book, 1905
  - g. Year Book, 1906
  - h. Year Book, 1908
  - i. Year Book, 1909,also contains notes for 1910
  - j. Diary, 1920
  - k. Diary, 1925
  - l. Pocket Diary, 1927
  - m. Pocket Diary, 1928,also 1929notes
  - n. Diary, 1930(labeled 1926)
  - o. Diary, 1931
  - p. Diary, 1932(five year)
  - q. 9 paper bound pocket diaries from Oxford University Press: 1930,2 vols.; 1931,1 vol.; 1932,4 vols.; 1933,2 vols.
  - r. 2 loose diary sheets, 1900 and 1904
  - s. Legal document, 1901
- Early Poetry, Melville Best Anderson (Box 22, Folder 124)
- Poems, Melville Best Anderson (Box 22, Folder 125)
- Poems and miscellaneous manuscripts by Melville Best Anderson (Box 22, Folder 126)
- Assorted letters from Melville Best Anderson to Howard Hall, Ewald Flügel, John Muir, C. L. Johnson, James O. Wright. (Box 22, Folder 127)
- Poems by Melville Best Anderson to Agnes Smith Mannucci-Capponi. (Box 22, Folder 128)
- Poems: 1. to C. F. Lummis; 2. Sinking of the Laconia 1917;3. to David Starr Jordan 1920 and 1922;4. poem to brother Edward Playfair Anderson with a consignment of old books; Our Old Meeting House by S. P. (Box 22, Folder 129)
- Comments regarding San Francisco and Emma Frances Dawson Benefit, 1894 (Box 22, Folder 130)
- Some Representative Poets of the Nineteenth Century. Syllabus of University Extension Lectures, 1896 (Box 22, Folder 131)
- Address at the Laying of the Cornerstone of the Thomas Welton Stanford Library, 1898 (Box 22, Folder 132)
- Mr. Murray's Byron, by Melville Best Anderson The Dial, May 16, 1899 (Box 22, Folder 133)
- Founders' Day Address, March 9, 1906.Leland Stanford Junior University Publications (Box 22, Folder 134)
- The Happy Teacher, 1910W. B. Heubach, pub. (Box 22, Folder 135)
- Purgatorio XI. The Lord's Prayer Translation. Matzke Memorial Volume, Leland Stanford Jr. University Publications, 1911,p. 37 (Box 22, Folder 136)
- 1. La Capponcina -- An Epistle to Friends by Melville Best Anderson, privately printed, Christmas 1912. (Box 22, Folder 137)
- 2. Francis Fisher Browne, American Magazine, April 1912.pp. 677,78
- 1. In Memory of Alphonso Gerald Newcomer reprinted from Stanford Alumnus, Mar. 1914. (Box 22, Folder 138)
- 2. Words spoken at the Obsequies of Dr. Ewald Flügel, Nov. 17, 1914
- 3. Why We Love Stanford. Stanford Alumnus vol. 6 no.4. Dec. 1914
- The Conversation of John Muir, American Museum Journal, Vol XV no. 3. March 1915.Also reprint of same article (Box 22, Folder 139)
- The Great Refusal, A War Poem. Printed for the Author, Florence. The Last Canto of the Paradisio of Dante Alegheri, Specimen translation. (Box 22, Folder 140)
- Malcolm Playfair Anderson, reprint from The Condor. Vol. XXL, May 1919 (Box 22, Folder 141)
- To David Starr Jordan for the Nineteenth of January, 1920,Commemorating a Friendship of Half a Century. 1870 - 1920 (Box 22, Folder 142)
- On a Portrait of David Starr Jordan at the Age of Twentyone. (Box 22, Folder 143)
  A Personal Message
- In Memory -- to Frank Victor Anderson, 1923 (Box 22, Folder 144)
- The Divine Comedy of Dante Alegheri. Reprint of Review by O. A. Bontempo and John Gerig from The Romantic Review, vol XXL No.2 April - June 1930 (Box 22, Folder 145)
- Paget Toynbee: Some Personal Reminiscences Romantic eview, Vol XXIII no. 4. Oct. - Dec. 1932 (Box 22, Folder 146)
- In Mmemoriam: Melville Best Anderson. By J. L. G. (Box 22, Folder 147)
  Reprint from The Romantic Review Vol XXIV no. 3, July-Sept. 1933
- Dante Manuscript (Box 23)
  - a. First Draft of Dante and His Florence.
  - b. Inferno (revised proofs)
  - c. Purgatorio, (duplicates)
  - d. Paradiso, (duplicates)
  - e. Corrected Galley proofs for Index to translation of Dante. Oxford Press Edition.
  - f. Specimen Pages Nash Dante, 1928
  - g. Authors copy of The Divine Comedy with holograph notes and corrections
  - h. La Divina Commedia, 3 vols. with author's notes
- Degree from the University of Aberdeen Doctor of Laws, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 148)
- Degree from the University of Aberdeen Doctor of Laws, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 149)
- Album of Newspaper clippings (Miscellaneous) in no particular order (Box 24, Folder 150)
- a. Miscellaneous newspaper clippings regarding lectures by Melville Best Anderson, 1899 (Box 24, Folder 151)
- b. Clippings regarding death of Balfour Anderson, March 22, 1895.
- c. Commencement Address, 1896,by Melville Best Anderson, in the Daily Palo Alto.
- d. The Vidette Reporter, containing review of Eleusis, Sept. 1890
- e. Lecture on Newspaper Reading by Melville Best Anderson, Daily Palo Alto Oct. 2, 1899
- f. Review of The Happy Teacher by William Morton Payne, The Dial Jan. 16, 1911
- g. D'Annunzio as a National Poet, by Melville Best Anderson, The Dial, April 1, 1912.
- h. Notice of Divinia Comedia, by David Starr Jordan, Unity, April 20, n.d.Tr. by Melville Best Anderson.
- i. The Times Literary Supplement, April 20, 1922,Review of the Divine Comedy, tr. by Melville Best Anderson
- j. Reprint of the Times review.
- k. New York Times, Book Review and Magazine, August 6, 1922.Review of The Divine Comedy, Tr. by Melville Best Anderson
- l. Cornell Alumni News (no date)containing review of Nash Edition of The Divine Comedy, tr. by Melville Best Anderson
- m. Coup d'Etat, undated,containing Book List Compiled by Melville Best Anderson
- n. Review of The Great Refusal, undatedand unsigned.
- Obituary Notices (Box 24, Folder 152)
  - New York Times, June 26, 1933
  - The Times, London, June 28, 1933
    1 clipping unidentified
- Assorted notes and Poetry (Box 25)
  - Assorted notes (Box 25, Folder 153)
  - Ma tthew Arnold (Box 25, Folder 154)
  - Francis Bacon (Box 25, Folder 155)
  - The Bible considered as Literature (Box 25, Folder 156)
  - List of Fifty Best Books (Box 25, Folder 157)
  - Robert Browning (Box 25, Folder 158)
  - Conversion, etc. (Box 25, Folder 159)
  - The Importance of English Studies in the College Curriculum (Box 25, Folder 160)
  - Epic Poetry (Box 25, Folder 161)
  - French Literature (Box 25, Folder 162)
  - Goethe (Box 25, Folder 163)
  - Historical Approach (Box 25, Folder 164)
  - Literature and Life (Box 25, Folder 165)
  - Poetry and Modern Life (Box 25, Folder 166)
  - Shakespeare's Timon and Moliere's Misanthrope. (Box 25, Folder 167)
  - Shakespeare's Plays: Notes on Hamlet, Romeo and Juliet, Merchant of Venice, Twelfth Night, King Lear, Julius Caesar, Anthony and Cleopatra, The Tempest, A Winter's Tale, Cymbeline. (Box 25, Folder 168)
  - Richard III (Box 25, Folder 169)
  - Victor Hugo, Poetic Genius (Box 25, Folder 170)
  - Victor Hugo (Box 25, Folder 171)
- Lecture Notes (Box 26)
- Tennyson
- Browning
- Conditions of France
- Byron
- Classic Myths
- Comparative Literature
- Diderot
  - Lecture notes in envelopes: Hamlet (Box 27, Folder 172)
  - Shakespeare - Tragedy
  - Shakespeare - Functions of Verse and Prose
  - Introductory Lecture
  - Shakespeare Reading Course
  - Shakespeare - Essays Twelfth Night and Much Ado About Nothing
  - Shakespeare- King Lear and King John
  - utline of Address: Verse and Prose in Shakespeare
  - Shakespeare - History
  - Shakespeare - Comedy
  - Lecture Notes
  - Passport, Melville Best Anderson July 12, 1875 (Box 27, Folder 173)
  - Who's who: elville Best Anderson 1932 - 33 (Box 27, Folder 174)
  - Contract, Stanford University, 1899 (Box 27, Folder 175)
  - Letter of Credit (Box 27, Folder 176)
  - Insurance (Box 27, Folder 177)
  - Stocks: Arrowhead, Stanislaus Electric Power Co., Mining Stock (Box 27, Folder 178)
  - Teaching Certificates, Contracts, Recommendations. (Box 27, Folder 179)
  - Building and Loan Association (Box 27, Folder 180)
  - Tax Receipts (Box 27, Folder 181)
  - Promissory Notes (Box 27, Folder 182)
  - Stanford University Bookstore Shares (Box 27, Folder 183)
  - Foreign Bills, etc. (Box 27, Folder 184)
  - Mortgages (Box 27, Folder 185)
  - Appraisement of Estate - Supplemental (Box 27, Folder 186)
  - Instructions, Bills, etc., regarding Ashes of Melville Best Anderson (Box 27, Folder 187)
- Letters to Edward Coffin Anderson, Regarding church and school matters
  Alphabetically Arranged
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 28, Folder 188)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 189)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 190)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 191)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 192)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 193)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 194)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 195)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 196)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 197)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 198)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 199)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 200)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 201)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 202)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 203)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 204)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 205)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 206)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 207)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 208)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 209)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters (Box 28, Folder 210)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Certificate of Ordination (Box 29, Folder 211)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson Marriage Certificate, to Helen Best (Box 29, Folder 212)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Testimonials (Box 29, Folder 213)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Family Papers (Box 29, Folder 214)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Recommendations (Box 29, Folder 215)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Kalamazoo College (Box 29, Folder 216)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Newton College and Kalamazoo College (Box 29, Folder 217)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, McMinnville College (Box 29, Folder 218)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Linfield College (Box 29, Folder 219)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Manuscript Notes (Box 29, Folder 220)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Business Papers (Box 29, Folder 221)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Diaries (Box 29, Folder 222)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Baptist Church (Box 29, Folder 223)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Citizenshp (Box 29, Folder 224)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Sermons (Box 29, Folder 225)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Poems and Rhymes (Box 29, Folder 226)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Obituary (Box 29, Folder 227)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Hector Academy and Acadia College (Box 29, Folder 228)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Drafts of Letters And Notes (Box 29, Folder 229)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Louisa van Vleck (Box 29, Folder 230)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Friends (Box 29, Folder 231)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, 2 letters (Box 29, Folder 232)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson 1855-1866 (Box 29, Folder 233)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson 1870 (Box 29, Folder 234)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson, 1871 (Box 29, Folder 235)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson, 1872 (Box 29, Folder 236)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson 1873 (Box 29, Folder 237)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson, 1875 (Box 29, Folder 238)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to H. B. Anderson (Box 29, Folder 239)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, dates uncertain. (Box 30, Folder 240)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to M. B. Anderson 1870 - 1877 (Box 30, Folder 241)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to M. B. Anderson 1878 - 1882 (Box 30, Folder 242)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to M. B. Anderson, 1883 - 1889 (Box 30, Folder 243)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to M. B. Anderson and grandsons 1885 - 1887 (Box 30, Folder 244)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to M. B. Anderson and family 1889 - 1890 (Box 30, Folder 245)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to M. B. Anderson and grandsons 1891 - 1892 (Box 30, Folder 246)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1893 - 1894 (Box 31, Folder 247)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1895 - 1896 (Box 31, Folder 248)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1899 - 1903 (Box 31, Folder 249)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Collection of Poems (Box 31, Folder 250)
  - Helen Best Anders n, Business Papers: Statements, Power of Attorney Deeds, Mortgages, Promissory Notes, Estate of Helen Best Anderson, Will. (Box 31, Folder 251)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to Edward Coffin Anderson, 1865 - 1874 (Box 31, Folder 252)
  - Helen Best Anderson, regarding Infant Son (Box 31, Folder 253)
  - Helen Best Anderson, Letters to Edward Playfair Anderson, 1880 (Box 31, Folder 254)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1870 (Box 31, Folder 255)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1871 (Box 31, Folder 256)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1874 (Box 31, Folder 257)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1875 (Box 31, Folder 258)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1876 (Box 31, Folder 259)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1877 (Box 31, Folder 260)
  - Edward Coffin Anders n, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1878 (Box 31, Folder 261)
  - Edward Coffin Ande son, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1879 (Box 31, Folder 262)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1880 (Box 31, Folder 263)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1881 (Box 31, Folder 264)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1882 (Box 31, Folder 265)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1883 (Box 31, Folder 266)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1884 (Box 31, Folder 267)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson and Edward Playfair Anderson, 1885 (Box 31, Folder 268)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Melville Best Anderson, 1886 (Box 31, Folder 269)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson, Letters to Edward Playfair Anderson, 1866-1880 (Box 31, Folder 270)
- Personal Letters to Helen Best Anderson.
  Alphabetically arranged
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, A (Box 32, Folder 271)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, B (Box 32, Folder 272)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, C (Box 32, Folder 273)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, D (Box 32, Folder 274)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, E (Box 32, Folder 275)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, F (Box 32, Folder 276)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, Failing (Box 32, Folder 277)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, G (Box 32, Folder 278)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, H (Box 32, Folder 279)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, I & J (Box 32, Folder 280)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, W. C. Johnson, lawyer (Box 32, Folder 281)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, Laleah Johnston (Box 32, Folder 282)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, K (Box 32, Folder 283)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, J. E. Magers, lawyer (Box 32, Folder 284)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, Mary (Box 32, Folder 285)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, May (Box 32, Folder 286)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, L & M (Box 32, Folder 287)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, N (Box 32, Folder 288)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, Sarah Olney (Box 32, Folder 289)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, P (Box 32, Folder 290)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, R (Box 32, Folder 291)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, Robert. (Box 32, Folder 292)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, S (Box 32, Folder 293)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, T (Box 32, Folder 294)
  - Letters to Helen Best Anderson, V & W (Box 32, Folder 295)
  - Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Estate, Will, Correspondence, Etc. (Box 33, Folder 296)
  - Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Passport (Box 33, Folder 297)
  - Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson, 1905-09 (Box 33, Folder 298)
  - Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson, 1910-11 (Box 33, Folder 299)